Vamsee Potluri

Lead Site Reliability Engineer\DevSecOps Engineer

DEVSECOPS Engineer with 10+ years of experience in securing, supporting and automating critical deployments over complex infrastructures. Proficient in Infrastructure as Code(IaC) and Platform as a Service(PaaS) in Hybrid cloud environments. Versatile professional with a passion to work in AWS, Azure & RedHat Openshift Implementations, thereby making a significant contribution to organizational transformation and goals. Adapt to diverse teams using interpersonal and communication skills.

link.vpotluri@gmail.com



(848) 229-4422



Remote



in linkedin.com/in/vamseepotluri

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Cloud Platforms & Operating

Systems::

AWS, Openshift V3 & V4, CoreOS, RedHat Enterprise Linux 8.x, 7.x, CentOS 6 &

Windows server 2016.

Containerization & CI/CD:

Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Chef, Puppet, Subversion, Git, Maven, Stash, BitBucket, Artifactory, Ansible, Bamboo.

Data Engineering:

Databricks, Snowflake, Apache Spark, Apache Airflow, Kafka, Tableau, Looker.

Monitoring Tools & other skills:

Datadog, JBoss 5.x/6.x Prometheus, Grafana, Splunk 5/6.x, AppDynamics 3.x, ElasticSearch, Log Stash, Kibana, FLuentd,

Apache Airflow.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (07/2020 - 07/2023)

HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (08/2020 - 08/2022)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Site Reliability Engineer\DevSecOps Engineer

Freewheel (a Comcast Company)

10/2021 - Present

New York city, NY

- Created infrastructure to support AWS-based Cloud services and Partner with development teams to help design and engineer scalable, reliable, and resilient online services.
- Developed internal platforms & services to enable expediency and self-service for our development teams. Working daily with Development teams to integrate security tool components via DevOps automated pipelines.
- Developed automation code for building 50+ pipelines, kubernetes clusters & cloud infrastructure, maximizing 40% efficiency, and improving security throughout the website. Worked on MLOps and ML CI/CD and integrated BI solutions such as MS Power BI & tableau.
- Architecting and maintaining software/infrastructure build, test, and deployment of CI/CD pipelines. Supporting and improving efficiency and effectiveness of internal tools and continually provide value to our partner development teams by staying current with cloud-based technologies and trends.
- Designed and developed data pipelines, data warehouses & data marts to integrate new data sets from different sources into a data platform. Implemented enterprise-level Azure solutions such as Azure Databricks, Azure ML, AKS and Azure SQ DB.
- Implemented provision of Amazon Web Services utilizing Terraform (open source, Enterprise or Cloud). Understanding of Infrastructure as Code and practical application of IaC using Docker, Kubernetes and Terraform in providing best practice to application engineering teams.
- Facilitate cross-functional partnerships between engineers, product managers, and designers to set the right goals and solve problems across our platform. Advocated for implement engineering best practices and develop a technical strategy to guide short and long-term project goals and its implementation plans.
- Managed release branches as well as maintains the build process to support continuous integration, Investigate, debug and drive improvements to engineering/build automation process. Develop Automation and bring in Observability (monitoring and alerting) at large sale systems; knowledge of networking, VPN's DNS. Load balancing and firewalls.
- Developed CICD pipelines on Azure Devops for code migration and created various pipelines to load data from Azure Data lake.
- Working with programming and scripting languages (e.g. Python, Boto3, Go-Lang, Bash scripting). Using software configuration management systems and source code version control systems like GitHub, Artifactory & Jenkins.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps Tech Lead/Lead Infrastructure Engineer [Platform As a Service]Barclays

10/2018 - 09/2021 Whippany, NJ

- Engineered Barclays Private Cloud services in Openshift V3 & V4 to automate entire PaaS product management Lifecycle. And have also interacted with executives and/or major customers to continually evolve PaaS road-map strategies.
- For Openshift Clusters, I have engineered a monitoring solution by using Prometheus & Grafana. So I have done this by collecting the required statistics via kubelet process running on the node and displaying the result sets in Grafana.
- Automated & Maintained the Image rollout process for different base images which are used internally in Barclays. Participated & Automated the Linux Patching schedule where the Kubernetes worker nodes were being patched as part of remediating OS level vulnerabilities identified in RHEL7.x systems.
- Used Helm Charts for managing the Kubernetes objects and resources. Also Facilitated users by combining all resource files into a single package and maintained the information about version, releases and rollback of the Openshift Container platform resources.
- Automated & Migrated Openshift master, etcd, haproxy infra, worker and user region nodes through CHEF cookbooks and have maintained the sanctity of the Openshift clusters by automating the cluster maintenance tasks like log_rotation, Node reboots etc.
- Maintained the Non-PROD & PROD Clusters for day-to-day activities on Openshift for creating new Projects, Services for load balancing and adding them to Routes to be accessible from outside, troubleshooting pods through ssh and logs, modification of Buildconfigs, templates, Imagestreams, etc.
- Engineered CI/CD using CodePipeline & CodeDeploy for automation and involved in 24*7 support rotation for all Production and Development Environments And have also configured various performance metrics using AWS Cloud watch & Cloud Trial.

Web Systems Administrator.

J.Crew Group Inc

04/2013 - 09/2018 New York city, NY

- Supported Manhattan Associates Application components like DOM/MSF/IFEE/JMS which are running on JBoss 5.1 and WebMethods.
 Configured JBoss 5.1 for supporting components like Distributed order Management, Manhattan Security Framework & JMS Services.
- Lead the team in Automating Continuous Integration build, deployment and infrastructure processes for multiple projects using VMware, RHEL, Satellite, Artifactory, Ansible, Docker and Jenkins. Developing Docker images to support the teams and their pipelines by using distributed Jenkins, Selenium, JMeter and splunk monitoring.
- Involved in Performance tuning of WebLogic server with respect to heap, threads and connection pools. Developed Standards and Guidelines for Capacity and Scalability planning efforts. Developed scripts for automatic startup and shutdown of Admin Server and Managed Servers.
- Configured monitoring tools like Splunk 5.x/6.x & AppDynamics 3.7.x. Maintained the applications among WebLogic run-time processes in a cluster of application servers. Regularly involved with troubleshooting, debugging, script building, automation innovation, monitoring, develop document and procedures, etc.
- Assumed ownership of monitoring environment and improved efficiency of alerting by 90% with no loss in environment visibility by investigating and eliminating needless alerts. Configure Aptly to allow updates and releases for multiple distributions and Improve the process by which web deployments are accomplished, reducing deployment time, and increasing the frequency of deployments.

Software Engineer

Zillion Technologies Inc

04/2010 - 03/2013 Ashburn, VA

- Part of a LOB team responsible for migrating Mortgage application like BDS Matrix, Accounts, Composite etc. Automating the installation, deployment and maintenance of Middleware Application Servers to RHEL Development, Test and Production Environments on VMware.
- Automating the creation of WebLogic Application server's instances, providing processes to automate configuration, restoring backups, automating compilation, testing and archiving of builds and code changes using shell scripting and Python programming.
- Monitoring the Infrastructure components and maintaining high reliability & performance in BDS Production Environments by proactivily scaling and minimizing the downtime's of all the critical components.

EDUCATION

Master's of Computer Science University of Illinois at Springfield **Bachelor's of Technology in Computer Science** P.V.P Siddartha Institute of technology

01/2007 - 05/2008 Springfield, Illinois, USA 05/2002 - 06/2006 Andhra Pradesh, India

Page 2 of 2